[
    {
        "question": "Ðæt (<em>scip</em>) #### sceal genægled⁠ — The ship must be nailed",
        "correctAnswer": "scip",
        "explanation": "Here the neuter noun 'scip' is the subject and so takes no ending",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Ðæs cyninges (<em>word</em>) #### is soþ⁠ — The king's word is truth",
        "correctAnswer": "word",
        "explanation": "Here the neuter noun 'word' is the subject and so takes no ending",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Godes (<em>bearn</em>) #### þrowode on þære rood⁠ — God's son suffered on the cross",
        "correctAnswer": "bearn",
        "explanation": "Here the neuter noun 'bearn' is the subject and so takes no ending",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Ðæt (<em>wif</em>) #### wæs gehæled of ðam wite⁠ — The woman was healed of the disease",
        "correctAnswer": "wif",
        "explanation": "Here the neuter noun 'wif' is the subject and so takes no ending",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Hira (<em>god</em>) #### sindon drycræfta lareowas⁠ — Their gods are teachers of magical arts",
        "correctAnswer": "godu",
        "explanation": "Here the neuter noun 'god' is the subject and plural, so since 'god' has a short syllable it takes a 'u' ending",
        "commonMistakes": [
            {
                "incorrectAnswer": "god",
                "explanation": "Here the neuter noun 'god' is the subject and plural, but since 'god' has a short syllable it should take a 'u' ending"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Ða (<em>scip</em>) #### Norðmanna cam on þissum dæg⁠ — The Northmen's ships came on this day",
        "correctAnswer": "scipu",
        "explanation": "Here the neuter noun 'scip' is the subject and plural, so since 'scip' has a short syllable it takes a 'u' ending",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Gif þa (<em>word</em>) #### sind soþ⁠ — If the words are true",
        "correctAnswer": "word",
        "explanation": "Here the neuter noun 'word' is the subject and plural, so since 'word' has a long syllable it takes no ending",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Geata (<em>bearn</em>) #### ferde to him⁠ — The children of the Geats went to him",
        "correctAnswer": "bearn",
        "explanation": "Here the neuter noun 'bearn' is the subject and plural, so since 'bearn' has a long syllable it takes no ending",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Seo geofu wæs broht for ðære synne ðæs ærestan (<em>wif</em>) ####⁠ — The grace was brought for the sin of the first woman",
        "correctAnswer": "wifes",
        "explanation": "Here the neuter noun 'wif' is in the genitive singular, so it takes the 'es' ending",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "He wæs hiora (<em>god</em>) #### preost⁠ — He was the priest of their god",
        "correctAnswer": "godes",
        "explanation": "Here the neuter noun 'god' is in the genitive singular, so it takes the 'es' ending",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Þæs (<em>scip</em>) #### mæst geburnen⁠ — The ship's mast burned",
        "correctAnswer": "scipes",
        "explanation": "Here the neuter noun 'scip' is in the genitive singular, so it takes the 'es' ending",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Þæt þurh (<em>bearn</em>) #### gebyrd butan weres frigum, byrd eacen wearð⁠ — Through the bearing of a child without a man's embrace, that bride became great",
        "correctAnswer": "bearnes",
        "explanation": "Here the neuter noun 'bearn' is in the genitive singular, so it takes the 'es' ending",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Seo is sæd ærest (<em>wif</em>) #### in Norþanhymbra mægþe ðæt heo munuchade onfenge⁠ — She is said to have been one of the first women in Northumbria to have taken nunhood",
        "correctAnswer": "wifa",
        "explanation": "Here the neuter noun 'wif' is in the genitive plural, so it takes the 'a' ending",
        "commonMistakes": [
            {
                "incorrectAnswer": "wif",
                "explanation": "Here the neuter noun 'wif' is in the genitive plural as she is 'one of the first', so it takes the 'a' ending"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "On þis dæg, com þæs hæthenes (<em>god</em>) #### wigan⁠ — On that day, the warriors of the heathen gods came",
        "correctAnswer": "goda",
        "explanation": "Here the neuter noun 'god' is in the genitive plural, so it takes the 'a' ending",
        "commonMistakes": [
            {
                "incorrectAnswer": "godes",
                "explanation": "Here the neuter noun 'god' is in the genitive plural, so it takes the 'a' ending, not the singular 'es' ending"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Ða het se cyning (<em>scip</em>) #### gegearcian⁠ — Then the king ordered the preparation of ships",
        "correctAnswer": "scipa",
        "explanation": "Here the neuter noun 'scip' is in the genitive plural, so it takes the 'a' ending",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Hlosna to þæs Godes (<em>word</em>) ####⁠ — Listen to the word of God",
        "correctAnswer": "word",
        "explanation": "Here the neuter noun 'word' is in the singular accusative, and so takes no ending",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "He Noe gebletsade and his (<em>bearn</em>) ####⁠ — He blessed Noah and his child",
        "correctAnswer": "bearn",
        "explanation": "Here the neuter noun 'bearn' is in the singular accusative, and so takes no ending",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "He spræc to þæm (<em>wif</em>) ####⁠ — He spoke to the woman",
        "correctAnswer": "wif",
        "explanation": "Here the neuter noun 'wif' is in the singular accusative, and so takes no ending",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Ða godu fram Egiptum landum beoþ fremede (<em>god</em>) #### — The gods from Egypt are strange gods",
        "correctAnswer": "godu",
        "explanation": "Here the neuter noun 'god' is the direct object and plural, so since 'god' has a short syllable it takes a 'u' ending",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "He wolde geseean helle (<em>god</em>) ####⁠ — He would visit the gods of hell",
        "correctAnswer": "godu",
        "explanation": "Here the neuter noun 'god' is the direct object and plural, so since 'god' has a short syllable it takes a 'u' ending",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Ðæt wæron þa erestan (<em>scip</em>) #### Deniscra manna the Angelcynnes land geseah⁠ — Those were the first ships of Danish men the English people's land saw",
        "correctAnswer": "scipu",
        "explanation": "Here the neuter noun 'scip' is the direct object and plural, so since 'god' has a short syllable it takes a 'u' ending",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Hie writon micel (<em>word</em>) #### lofa⁠ — They wrote many words of praise",
        "correctAnswer": "word",
        "explanation": "Here the neuter noun 'word' is the direct object and plural, so since 'word' has a long syllable it takes no ending",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Se fæder wið-soc eall to his (<em>bearn</em>) ####⁠ — The father denied all to his child",
        "correctAnswer": "bearne",
        "explanation": "Here the neuter noun 'bearn' is the indirect object and singular, and so takes an 'e' ending",
        "commonMistakes": [
            {
                "incorrectAnswer": "bearn",
                "explanation": "Here the neuter noun 'bearn' is the indirect object and singular, and so takes an 'e' ending. It is 'eall' which is the direct object"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Ond mon mot feohtan orwige gif he gemeteþ oðerne æt his æwum (<em>wif</em>) ####⁠ — And a man can fight without charge of homicide if he finds another with his lawful wife",
        "correctAnswer": "wife",
        "explanation": "Here the neuter noun 'wif' is the indirect object and singular, and so takes an 'e' ending",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Seo cwen geaf þa boc to þæm (<em>wif</em>) ####⁠ — The queen gave the book to the woman",
        "correctAnswer": "wife",
        "explanation": "Here the neuter noun 'wif' is the indirect object and singular, and so takes an 'e' ending",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "We willaþ mid þam sceattum us to þæm (<em>scip</em>) #### gangan⁠ — We wish to go to the ship with the treasure",
        "correctAnswer": "scipe",
        "explanation": "Here the neuter noun 'scip' is the indirect object and singular, and so takes an 'e' ending",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "He ærist scoop eorþan for his (<em>bearn</em>) ####⁠ — He first shaped the earth for his children",
        "correctAnswer": "bearnum",
        "explanation": "Here the neuter noun 'bearn' is the indirect object and plural, and so takes a 'um' ending",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Heo geaf micel giefa to þæm (<em>wif</em>) ####⁠ — She gave many gifts to the women",
        "correctAnswer": "wifum",
        "explanation": "Here the neuter noun 'wif' is the indirect object and plural, and so takes a 'um' ending",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Hie bædon to hiora (<em>god</em>) ####⁠ — They prayed to their gods",
        "correctAnswer": "godum",
        "explanation": "Here the neuter noun 'god' is the indirect object and plural, and so takes a 'um' ending",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Se here ferde to þæm (<em>scip</em>) ####⁠ — The army went to the ships",
        "correctAnswer": "scipum",
        "explanation": "Here the neuter noun 'scip' is the indirect object and plural, and so takes a 'um' ending",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Seo (<em>cwen</em>) #### ferþ to þæm beorgum⁠ — The queen goes to the mountains",
        "correctAnswer": "cwen",
        "explanation": "Here the feminine noun 'cwen' is the subject and so takes no ending",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Wæs (<em>giefu</em>) #### Hroþgares oft geæhted⁠ — The gift of Hrothgar was often prized",
        "correctAnswer": "giefu",
        "explanation": "Here the feminine noun 'giefu' is the subject and so takes no ending",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Seo (<em>ceaster</em>) #### ne mæg beon behyd⁠ — The city cannot be hidden",
        "correctAnswer": "ceaster",
        "explanation": "Here the feminine noun 'ceaster' is the subject and so takes no ending",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Sceolde manig blachleor (<em>ides</em>) #### bifiende gan⁠ — Many a pale-faced lady must trembling go",
        "correctAnswer": "ides",
        "explanation": "Here the feminine noun 'ides' is the subject and so takes no ending",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Þa (<em>cwen</em>) #### wæron hatene Marsepia and Lampida⁠ — The queens were called Marsepia and Lampida",
        "correctAnswer": "cwena",
        "explanation": "Here the feminine noun 'cwen' is the subject and plural, so it takes an 'a' ending",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Hie ælmihtiges (<em>giefu</em>) #### anforleten⁠ — They might lose the almighty's gifts",
        "correctAnswer": "giefa",
        "explanation":"Here 'giefu' is plural and directly receiving the action of the verb 'forleten', so it loses its 'u' and takes an 'a' ending",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Ða (<em>ceaster</em>) ####, Gleawanceaster, Cirenceaster and Baþanceaster, beoþ on ceastrum weallum beworhte⁠ — The cities, Gloucester, Cirencester and Bath, are walled towns",
        "correctAnswer": "ceastra",
        "explanation": "Here the feminine noun 'ceastra' is the subject and plural, so it loses its second 'e' takes an 'a' ending",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Ða (<em>ides</em>) #### sloh ða wundenlocc þone feondsceaðan⁠ — The women slew the wavy-haired fiend",
        "correctAnswer": "idesa",
        "explanation": "Here the feminine noun 'ides' is the subject and plural, so it takes an 'a' ending",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Heo ferde to þære (<em>cwen</em>) #### broce ond fram þære cwene broce⁠ — She went to the Queen's brook and from the Queen's brook",
        "correctAnswer": "cwene",
        "explanation": "Here the feminine noun 'cwen' is in the posessive singular, so it takes an 'e' ending",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Ðære (<em>ceaster</em>) #### ealdorman spræc mid þæm biscope⁠ — The city's elderman spoke with the bishop",
        "correctAnswer": "ceastre",
        "explanation": "Here the feminine noun 'ceaster' is in the posessive singular, so it loses its second 'e' and takes an 'e' ending",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Ðæra oðer wæs (<em>ides</em>) #### onlicnes⁠ — The other had a woman's likeness",
        "correctAnswer": "idese",
        "explanation": "Here the feminine noun 'ides' is in the posessive singular, so it takes an 'a' ending",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "He wæs on ðara (<em>cwen</em>) #### gewealdum⁠ — He was under the power of the queens",
        "correctAnswer": "cwena",
        "explanation": "Here the feminine noun 'cwen' is in the posessive plural, so it takes an 'a' ending",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Ðara (<em>ceaster</em>) #### wisra menn ferde to þæm cyning⁠ — The cities wise men went to the king",
        "correctAnswer": "ceastra",
        "explanation": "Here the feminine noun 'ceaster' is in the posessive plural, so it loses its second 'e' and takes an 'a' ending",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Ðara (<em>ides</em>) #### fæder wæs sæt æt wine⁠ — The ladies father was sat at his wine",
        "correctAnswer": "idesa",
        "explanation": "Here the feminine noun 'ides' is in the posessive plural, so it takes an 'a' ending",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Ic seah feaxhar (<em>cwen</em>) ####⁠ — I saw a hoary-haired woman",
        "correctAnswer": "cwene",
        "explanation": "Here the feminine noun 'cwen' is the direct object and singular, so it takes an 'e' ending",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Heo gefylled wæs wisdomes (<em>giefu</em>) ####⁠ — She was filled with wisdom's gift",
        "correctAnswer": "giefe",
        "explanation": "Here the feminine noun 'giefu' is the direct object and singular, so it loses its 'u' and takes an 'e' ending",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Ælla and Cissa ymbsæton þa (<em>ceaster</em>) ####⁠ — Aella and Cissa beseiged the city",
        "correctAnswer": "ceastre",
        "explanation": "Here the feminine noun 'ceaster' is the direct object and singular, so it loses its second 'e' and takes an 'e' ending",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Weras and (<em>ides</em>) #### sceolan læran Godes lufan⁠ — Men and women shall learn God's love",
        "correctAnswer": "idesa",
        "explanation": "Here the feminine noun 'ides' is the subject and plural, so it takes an 'a' ending",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Ða þegnas læston þa (<em>cwen</em>) ####⁠ — The thanes followed the Queens",
        "correctAnswer": "cwena",
        "explanation": "Here the feminine noun 'cwen' is the direct object and plural, so it takes an 'a' ending",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Se Hælend ymbfor ealle þa burga ond þa (<em>ceaster</em>) ####⁠ — Jesus went around all the villages and the cities",
        "correctAnswer": "ceastra",
        "explanation": "Here the feminine noun 'ceaster' is the direct object and plural, so it loses its second 'e' and takes an 'a' ending",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "To saulum on heofonum þu selest weorþlica (<em>giefu</em>) ####⁠ — To the souls in heaven you will give worthy gifts",
        "correctAnswer": "giefa",
        "explanation": "Here the feminine noun 'giefu' is the direct object and plural, so it loses its 'u' and takes an 'a' ending",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Ða comon ða weardas to þære (<em>ceaster</em>) ####⁠ — Then the keepers came into the city",
        "correctAnswer": "ceastre",
        "explanation": "Here the feminine noun 'ceaster' is an indirect object and singular, so it loses its second 'e' and takes an 'e' ending",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Ða þegnas ferde to þære (<em>ides</em>) ####⁠ — The thanes went to the lady",
        "correctAnswer": "idese",
        "explanation": "Here the feminine noun 'ides' is an indirect object and singular, so it takes an 'e' ending",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Hie to ðære (<em>cwen</em>) #### agefon him⁠ — Then they gave him up to the queen",
        "correctAnswer": "cwene",
        "explanation": "Here the feminine noun 'cwen' is an indirect object and singular, so it takes an 'e' ending",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "He ferde to þæm ceastre mid þæs cyninges (<em>giefu</em>) ####⁠ — He went to the city with the king's gift",
        "correctAnswer": "giefe",
        "explanation": "Here the feminine noun 'giefu' is an indirect object and singular, so it loses its 'u' and takes an 'e' ending",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Hlynn wearþ on þæm (<em>ceaster</em>) ####⁠ — A great cry arose in the cities",
        "correctAnswer": "ceastrum",
        "explanation": "Here the feminine noun 'ceaster' is an indirect object and plural, so it loses its second 'e' and takes a 'um' ending",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "He geaf þa bec to þæm (<em>ides</em>) ####⁠ — He gave the books to the ladies",
        "correctAnswer": "idesum",
        "explanation": "Here the feminine noun 'ides' is an indirect object and plural, so it takes a 'um' ending",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Ða þegnas geaf begas ond feoh to þæm (<em>cwen</em>) ####⁠ — The thanes gave rings and wealth to the queens",
        "correctAnswer": "cwenum",
        "explanation": "Here the feminine noun 'cwen' is an indirect object and plural, so it takes a 'um' ending",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Ðin mod trymeþ mid godcundum (<em>giefu</em>) ####⁠ — Strengthen your mind with divine gifts",
        "correctAnswer": "giefum",
        "explanation": "Here the feminine noun 'giefu' is an indirect object and plural, so it takes a 'um' ending",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "He cyste þæs (<em>biscop</em>) #### sweartne stan — He kissed the bishop’s black stone",
        "correctAnswer": "biscopes",
        "explanation": "Here the masculine noun 'biscop' is in the singular genitive so it takes the 'es' ending",
        "commonMistakes": [
            {
                "incorrectAnswer": "biscopa",
                "explanation": "While 'biscop' is in the genitive, it is the singular 'biscopes'. Biscopa' is the genitive plural"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Se (<em>þegen</em>) #### ond þa biscopas comon fram Readingum — The thane and the bishops came from Reading",
        "correctAnswer": "þegen",
        "explanation": "Here the masculine noun 'þegen' is the subject so it takes the nominative singular case",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Ðæs cyninges (<em>þegen</em>) #### ferdon to þæm tune  — The king’s thanes went to the town",
        "correctAnswer": "þegnas|þegenas",
        "explanation": "Here the masculine noun 'þegen' is the subject and in the plural, so it takes the 'as' ending of the plural nominative",
        "commonMistakes": [
            {
                "incorrectAnswer": "þegen",
                "explanation": "While not apparant in the Old English, þegen is clearly plural in the modern English trans, and so takes the 'as' ending of the nominative plural"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Ða (<em>cyning</em>) #### ond þa biscopas wæron on Æscesdune — The kings and the bishops were in Ashdown",
        "correctAnswer": "cyningas",
        "explanation": "Here the masculine noun 'cyning' is the subject and plural so it takes the 'as' ending of the nominative plural",
        "commonMistakes": [
            {
                "incorrectAnswer": "cyning",
                "explanation": "'Cyning' is the singular form of the word while the above word is plural. This means the correct answer is 'cyningas'. If you're not sure whether a word is plural or singular, check the demonstrative pronoun."
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Ðara (<em>biscop</em>) #### preostas ferdon to þæm halige stede mid him — The bishops’ priests went to the holy place with them",
        "correctAnswer": "biscopa",
        "explanation": "Here the masculine noun 'biscop' is in the possessive plural, since there are multiple priests belong to multiple bishops, so it takes the 'a' ending of the genitive plural",
        "commonMistakes": [
            {
                "incorrectAnswer": "biscopas",
                "explanation": "Biscopas is the nominative or accusative plural. The genitive plural ends in 'a', so the correct answer is 'biscopa'."
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "He wunaþ in þæs (<em>cyning</em>) #### tune — He lives in the town of the king",
        "correctAnswer": "cyninges",
        "explanation": "Here the masculine noun 'cyning' is in the possessive singular so it takes the 'es' ending of the genitive singular",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Ða þegnas þara <em>(cyning)</em> #### Ælfred and Æþelred — The thane's of the Kings' Alfred and Ethelred",
        "correctAnswer": "cyninga",
        "explanation": "Here the masculine noun 'cyning' is in the possessive plural so it takes the 'a' ending of the genitive plural",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Se (<em>biscop</em>) #### com fram þæm tune — The bishop came from the town",
        "correctAnswer": "biscop",
        "explanation": "Here the masculine noun 'biscop' is the subject and in the singular so it takes no ending, as per the nominative singular",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Hie sind þa þegnas þara (<em>cyning</em>) #### — They are the thanes of the Kings",
        "correctAnswer": "cyning",
        "explanation": "Here the masculine noun 'cyning' is subject and in the singular so it takes no ending, as per the nominative singular",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "He com fram þæs (<em>þegen</em>) #### tune — He came from the thane’s town",
        "correctAnswer": "þegnes|þegenes",
        "explanation": "Here the masculine noun 'þegen' is in the possessive singular so it takes the 'es' ending of the genitive singular",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Se cyning ond þa (<em>biscop</em>) #### —  The king and the bishops",
        "correctAnswer": "biscopas",
        "explanation": "Here the masculine noun 'biscop' is part of the subject and plural so it takes the 'as' ending of the nominative plural",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Ðæs (<em>þegen</em>) #### menn — The thane’s men",
        "correctAnswer": "þegnes|þegenes",
        "explanation": "Here the masculine noun 'þegen' is in the possessive singular so it takes the 'es' ending of the genitive singular",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Menn fram þara (<em>þegen</em>) #### tunum — Men from the towns of the thanes",
        "correctAnswer": "þegna|þegena",
        "explanation": "Here the masculine noun 'þegen' is in the possessive plural as the men are from towns belonging to the thanes, so it takes the 'a' ending of the genitive plural",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Ða <em>(stan)</em> #### fram þæs þegnes tune — The stone from the thane’s town",
        "correctAnswer": "stanas",
        "explanation": "Here the masculine noun 'stan' is subject and is plural so it takes the 'as' ending of the nominative plural",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Se (<em>stan</em>) #### ond se þegen comon fram þæm tune — The stone and the thane came from the town",
        "correctAnswer": "stan",
        "explanation": "Here the masculine noun 'stan' is subject and in the singular so it takes no ending, as per the nominative singular",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Ðara <em>(wicing)</em> #### cyning wolde þæt þa Deniscan ricsoden ofer Englalande⁠ — The king of the viking's would that the Danes ruled over England",
        "correctAnswer": "wicinga",
        "explanation": "Here the masculine noun 'wicing' is in the possessive plural as the subject is the king of many vikings, so 'wicing' takes the 'a' ending of the genitive plural",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Ða bearn þæs <em>(cyning)</em> #### beoþ wis and eaþmod⁠ — The children of the king are wise and humble",
        "correctAnswer": "cyninges",
        "explanation": "Here the masculine noun 'cyning' is in the possessive singular so it takes the 'es' ending of the genitive singular",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Ða <em>(biscop)</em> #### geaf þone stan to þæm þegne — The bishops gave the stone to the thane",
        "correctAnswer": "biscopas",
        "explanation": "Here the masculine noun 'biscop' is the subject and it is plural so it takes the 'as' ending of the nominative plural",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Giet wæs se <em>(cyning)</em> #### Ælfred geong⁠ — Still, the king Alfred was young",
        "correctAnswer": "cyning",
        "explanation": "Here the masculine noun 'cyning' is the subject and in the singular so it takes no ending, as per the nominative singular",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Se biscop grete þone (<em>cyning</em>) #### — The bishop greets the king",
        "correctAnswer": "cyning",
        "explanation": "Here the masculine noun 'cyning' is directly receiving the action of the verb 'grete', so is in the singular accusative and thus takes no new ending",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Þa biscopas geaf þone (<em>stan</em>) #### to þæm þegne — The bishops gave the stone to the thane",
        "correctAnswer": "stan",
        "explanation": "Here the masculine noun 'stan' is directly receiving the action of the verb 'geaf', so is in the singular accusative and thus takes no new ending",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Se þegen sloh þone (<em>biscop</em>) #### in þæm tune — The thane slew the bishop in the town",
        "correctAnswer": "biscop",
        "explanation": "Here the masculine noun 'biscop' is directly receiving the action of the verb 'sloh', so is in the singular accusative and thus takes no new ending",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Se cyning ond seo cwen grete þa (<em>biscop</em>) #### — The king and the queen greet the bishops",
        "correctAnswer": "biscopas",
        "explanation": "Here the masculine noun 'biscop' is directly receiving the action of the verb 'grete' and is also plural, so it is in the plural accusative and thus takes the 'as' ending",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Se cyning sloh þa (<em>þegen</em>) #### — The king slew the thanes",
        "correctAnswer": "þegnas|þegenas",
        "explanation": "Here the masculine noun 'þegen' is directly receiving the action of the verb 'sloh' and is also plural, so it is in the plural accusative and thus takes the 'as' ending",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Se þegen geaf þa (<em>gar</em>) #### to þæm cyninge — The thane gave the spears to the king",
        "correctAnswer": "garas",
        "explanation": "Here the masculine noun 'gar' is directly receiving the action of the verb 'geaf' and is also plural, so it is in the plural accusative and thus takes the 'as' ending",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "To þæm biscop geaf se cyning þa (<em>beag</em>) #### — The king gave rings to the bishop",
        "correctAnswer": "beagas",
        "explanation": "Here the masculine noun 'beag' is directly receiving the action of the verb 'geaf' and is also plural, so it is in the plural accusative and thus takes the 'as' ending",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "To þæm (<em>cyning</em>) #### se biscop geaf beag — To the king, the bishop gave a ring",
        "correctAnswer": "cyninge",
        "explanation": "Here the masculine noun 'cyning' is not directly receiving the action of the verb 'geaf', so it is in the singular dative and thus takes the 'e' ending.",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Se þegen ferþ to þæm (<em>biscop</em>) #### mid wordum fram þæm cyning — The thane goes to the bishop with words from the king",
        "correctAnswer": "biscope",
        "explanation": "Here the masculine noun 'biscop' is not directly receiving the action of the verb 'ferþ', so it is in the singular dative and thus takes the 'e' ending",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Se biscop ferde fram þæm (<em>þegen</em>) #### to þæm cyning — The bishop went from the thane to the king",
        "correctAnswer": "þegne|þegene",
        "explanation": "Here the masculine noun 'þegen' is not directly receiving the action of the verb 'ferde', so it is in the singular dative and thus takes the 'e' ending",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "On þis daege, Æðelred cyning ferde to þæm (<em>tun</em>) #### mid his broðrum — On this day, King Ethelred went to the town with his brothers",
        "correctAnswer": "tune",
        "explanation": "Here the masculine noun 'tun' is not directly receiving the action of the verb 'ferde', so it is in the singular dative and thus takes the 'e' ending",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Se cyning ferþ to þæm (<em>beorg</em>) #### — The king goes to the mountains",
        "correctAnswer": "beorgum",
        "explanation": "Here the masculine noun 'beorg' is not directly receiving the action of the verb 'ferþ', so it is in the singular dative and thus takes the 'e' ending",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Wærferhþ biscop ferde to þæm (<em>biscop</em>) #### in Lundene ond Wiltunscire — Bishop Warfehth went to the bishops of London and Wiltshire",
        "correctAnswer": "biscopum",
        "explanation": "Here the masculine noun 'biscop' is not directly receiving the action of the verb 'ferde', so it is in the singular dative and thus takes the 'e' ending",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Se geaf þa garas to þæm (<em>þegen</em>) #### — He gave the spears to the thanes",
        "correctAnswer": "þegnum|þegenum",
        "explanation": "Here the masculine noun 'þegen' is not directly receiving the action of the verb 'geaf', so it is in the singular dative and thus takes the 'e' ending",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Þa biscopas comon fram þæm (<em>tun</em>) #### hetum Londenum ond Readingum — The bishops came from the towns called London and Reading",
        "correctAnswer": "tunum",
        "explanation": "Here the masculine noun 'tun' is not directly receiving the action of the verb 'came', so it is in the singular dative and thus takes the 'e' ending",
        "commonMistakes": []
    }
]